Register of the Allan W. Neil letters to his mother
Hoover Institution Archives
Allan W. Neil letters to his mother
Bulk, 1918-1919
1918-1957
57021
Neil, Allan W., 1891-1950.
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Relates to conditions in Marine Corps training camps in the United States and to Marine activities in France and Germany during and immediately after World War I.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1957.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Allan Neil was born on March 9, 1891 in Medina, Ohio. His family moved to Denver, Colorado when he was a child. After being classified as "class 1" by the Local Board for the Country of Saguache, Colorado, he later became a private in the United States Marine Corps. While away at war, Neil kept in touch with his mother Ellen Neil (later Ellen Combes) and his two sisters Louise and Dorothy through an exchange of letters from 1918 to 1919. In 1919, he returned home after completing his term of enlistment. Neil was never married, and lived with his mother until her death in 1931. At the age of 58, Allan Neil passed away in 1950 in Bay Pines, Florida.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Allan Neil papers include correspondence, photographs, newspaper clippings, and various military documents. The correspondence consists of letters from Allan Neil to Ellen Neil during Allan Neil?s service in the military between 1918 and 1919. The materials relate to conditions in Marine Corps training camps in the United States and to Marine activities in France and Germany during and immediately after World War I.
United States. Marine Corps.; World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--France.
- Biography of Allan Neil, 1957 (Folder 1: 1)
- Certificate, 1919 (Folder 1: 2)
- Clippings, 1918-1919 (Folder 1: 3)
- Financial documents, 1917-1918 (Folder 1: 4)
- Letters to Ellen Neil, 1918-1919
  - 1918 (Folder 1: 5-6)
  - 1919 (Folder 1: 7)
- Letter from Mabel Hilliard, undated (Folder 1: 8)
- Marine Corps printed matter, undated (Folder 1: 9)
- Military records, 1918 (Folder 1: 10)
- Photographs, 1919, undated (Folder 1: 11)
- Posters, 1919 (Folder 1: 12)